

JEFF DAVENPORT

Project Manager / IRATA Lvl 3

About Me

I'm a versatile individual with strong technical skills and a knack for connecting with people from all walks of life. Drawing from my experiences learning from industry experts, I enjoy coaching and educating others.

Meticulous attention to detail is my hallmark, ensuring tasks are completed to the highest standards.

Personal Details

+27 74 621 5594



jeffoffshore1@gmail.com



Langebaan, South Africa



South African



English & Afrikaans



DOB: 10 January 1990

Career Breakdown



Positions Held

Position: Senior Project Manager Company: Axess Offshore Africa

Location: South Africa Timeline: June 2021 - May 2024

Location: New Zealand

Timeline: 2020

- · Provide tailored Asset Integrity solutions, addressing maintenance, inspection, and rigging challenges in the oil & gas industry
- ·Successfully managing multiple client portfolios and projects in the African region, adapting to unique logistics and regulatory landscapes.
- · Identify and mitigate potential risks, ensuring projects are delivered within scope, schedule, and budget.
- · Demonstrate strong listening and communication skills to accurately identify clients' needs, prepare and submit proposals and exceed their expectations.
- Foster effective communication and cooperation between our company, clients, and key project resources throughout the project lifecycle.
- · Proficient in utilizing Microsoft Suite for conducting remote meetings, structuring tasks, providing updates, and tracking project/portfolio statuses.
- Providing regular updates on the project's status, progress toward goals, and the effectiveness of strategies.

Position: Ecological Crew Lead / H&S Advisor Company: Treescape / ETCO

- Advising apprentices on correct Health & Safety practises.
- ·Auditing and advising host companies on their individual H&S practices and
- · Investigating any incidents or injuries that occurred on the host companies' work
- Overall, my contributions were essential in fostering a safe and secure work environment for both the apprentices and host companies, aligning with the company's vision of excellence in the industry.
- Introducing Ecological crew members to Rope Access techniques.
- Responsible for companies Work @ Height equipment
- ·Providing support with tenders, job scoping and quoting.

Position: Asset Integrity Safety Supervisor Company: Prezioso Linjebygg

- **Location: Angola** Timeline: 2017 - 2020
- Supervisor of the core inspection team, ensuring company, client and IRATA procedures are implemented.
- Daily Health & Safety and job planning meetings with crew and client.
- Establishing, implementing and overseeing effective inspection reporting
- Mentoring of Local Angolan personnel for the localisation scheme.
- Permit to work and client safety implementation on all third party inspection campaigns
- Design and installation of work at height and confined space rescue systems
- **Emergency Response Team Deputy**
- Utilization of SAP to generate operation work orders & notifications.
- Inspection of Structural Integrity & general components of FPSO and continually liaising with the client and other entities in the best interests of the Asset

Education

Project Management

Project Management Institute Certified Associate Project Manager (CAPM) Year: 2020 -2021

Work @ Height

IRATA Rope Access Level **3** Year: 2012 - Current

Vertical Horizonz - EWP Certificate Year: 2020 - 2023



Health Safety & Environment (HSE)

- Manual Handling Awareness
- Risk Awareness, Hazard Identification, Risk Assessment & Risk Control
- SiteSafe Site Safe Certification
- SAIOSH Advanced Fire fighting
- HUET Offshore Survival

NDT Courses

- Ultrasonic Flaw Detection Ivl 1
- Ultrasonic Wall Thickness + A-scan Level 2
- Eddy Current Level 1
- Magnetic Particle Testing Level 2

Certification Body: ASNT Year: 2014 - 2015

OTHER

SAQCC Grit Blasting, Painting & Spray Painting

All certificates and recent references can be provided on request.



THANK YOU!

Freelance Field Service Technician Location: Africa

Positions

- IRATA Rope Access Safety Supervisor
- IRATA Rope Access NDT Inspector
- IRATA Rope Access DROPS Inspector
- IRATA Rope Access Bolt Torque Technician
- IRATA Rope Access Rigger
- IRATA Rope Access Blaster & Painter

Description:

I worked as a freelance technician on Oil & Gas platforms throughout Africa, adapting to each site and the conditions thereof.

Timeline: 2012 - 2017

Tasks Performed:

- Class Surveys of Crude Oil & Water Ballast Tanks
- Piping Inspection
- Pressure Vessel Inspection External & Internal (Shut Downs)
- Installation of work at height & confined space rescue systems
- Emergency Response Team Member
- · Reporting & utilization of SAP.
- Inspection of Structural Integrity & general components of FPSO.
- Fasbric maintenance of Water Ballast Tanks

Contracting Companies

- Prezioso Linjebygg https://rb.gy/pcenx
- Global Spec https://www.globalspec.com/
- Toprope SA https://toprope.co.za/
- Southey Contracting https://www.southeycontracting.com/